

Maria Jose Matar

Software Engineer

www.linkedin.com/in/mariajosematar/

- +34 695 740 656
- +54 2236042940

https://github.com/mariajosematar

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Senior Analyst

Accenture is a global company that provides software services across various industries

November 2022 to June 2023 (8 months).

- Cognitive Insurance Platform North America.
- Design, build and configure applicaDesign, build, and configure applications to meet business process and application requirements: Core Python Expertise, and knowledge of Web Frameworks. Familiarity with Object Relational Mapper Libraries, knowledge of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning domains, Fair knowledge of Deep Learning Fundamentals, knowledge of Python web frameworks, Familiarity with event-driven programming in Python, Must have unit testing and debugging skills, knowledge of Python packages such as NumPy, Scikit learntions to meet business process and application requirements.
- Skills: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) · Software
 Architecture · Amazon SQS · Amazon S3 · Docker · Python ·
 Google Cloud Platform (GCP) · Integration Testing · AWS
 Lambda · Bitbucket.

Machine Learning Engineer

Accenture is a global company that provides software services across various industries

November 2022 to January 2023
(3 months).

- Ulta Beauty Delivery System Integration Specialist.
- Delivery System Integration Specialist: Design and build Integration systems to meet business process and application requirements. Ulta Beauty - Delivery System Integration Specialist. Delivery System Integration Specialist: Design and build Integration systems to meet business process and application requirements.
- Skills: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) ·
 Software Architecture · Amazon SQS · Python ·
 Google Cloud Platform (GCP) · Amazon Web Services
 (AWS) · Integration Testing · AWS Lambda ·
 MongoDB.

SUMMARY

My name is Maria José. I am an engineering student and am currently employed as a software engineer. With four years of experience in development, I have a strong background in this field.

I truly enjoy collaborating with others and am comfortable working remotely or in a hybrid environment.

I am familiar with working under agile Scrum methodologies, which allows for effective teamwork and efficient project management.

One aspect of my work that I particularly enjoy is taking on exact time trial challenges. I find great satisfaction in overcoming these challenges and delivering high-quality results.

I am excited to contribute my skills and expertise to new projects.

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Javascript, C/C++, Java, Python, Node.js, MongoDB, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) · Software Architecture · Amazon SQS · Amazon EC2 · Microservices · Jira · React.js · Amazon S3 · Amazon CloudWatch · SQL · Docker · Microsoft Azure · AWS CloudFormation · Node.js · JavaScript · Machine Learning · Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Kubernetes · AWS Lambda · MongoDB · MySQL · Jenkins · Express.js · Mocha (JavaScript Framework) · Bootstrap · HTML · Metodologías ágiles · Bitbucket · Git · English
- Problem-Solving
- Team Communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Endava is, a global company that provides software services across various industries

March 2021 to October 2022
(1 year, 10 months).

- In a project as a backend developer (NodeJS) for the US client 'GSTV'. The Project consists of a video network that plays advertisements in the dispensers of service stations throughout the country.
- Skills: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) ·
 Software Architecture · Amazon SQS · Amazon EC2
 · Microservices · Jira · React.js · Amazon S3 ·
 Amazon CloudWatch · SQL · Docker · Microsoft
 Azure · AWS CloudFormation · Node.js · JavaScript
 · Machine Learning · Amazon Web Services (AWS) ·
 Kubernetes · AWS Lambda · MongoDB · MySQL ·
 Jenkins · Express.js · Mocha (JavaScript
 Framework) · Bootstrap · HTML · Metodologías
 ágiles · Bitbucket · Git · English.

INTERN

Technical Developer

March 2021 to July 2021 (5 months)

- Learned about the operations of the company's software programming team
- Coordinated communications between multiple departments.
- Skills: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) ·
 Software Architecture · Python (Programming
 Language) · PHP · Microsoft Word · Oracle
 Database · Jira · React.js · AWS CloudFormation ·
 Node.js · JavaScript · MongoDB · MySQL ·
 Bootstrap · Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) · HTML ·
 Metodologías ágiles · Bitbucket · Git · Inglés ·
 Trabajo en equipo.

EDUCATION HISTORY



CHALLENGE 2023 / FREELANCE

- SmartEat Using Python // Smartfood management system can help households and businesses track their food inventory, expiration dates, and consumption patterns.
- Accenator Using Python + Django // The idea was to replicate the concept of the renowned Akinator game and modify it for a business game format.

Some of the challenges I've developed in recent months include

- Battleship Using Python
- Rest of the API: use Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB.
- Dual-Pay Find an alternative to access the conversion of money from the bank to our Argentine account in a faster and more intuitive way. Javascript, PHP, HTML, CSS.

If you want to talk about software development, coding, or anything else.

Skills: Python, JavaScript, Node.js, TypeScript, SQL, MongoDB, Express, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, and more.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS AND VOLUNTEER WORK

- AWS Essential Training for <u>Developers</u>
- Azure AZ-204.
- Microservices Foundations
- Python Avanzado
- Web Developer Bootcamp 20233
- MongoDB Certified Developer Associate.
- Node.js and MongoDB.
- Cambridge English Level C1.
- Florecer Juntos.